

ROVY SAPUTRA NUGERAHA

: East Tanjungpinang, Tanjungpinang City

Phone Number: +62 81261461477

E-mail : rovysaputra10@gmail.com

Website : www.ptravy.com

LinkedIn : http://linkedin.com/in/rovysaputranugeraha

: Visit(Link) **Portfolio**

SUMMARY

I am a 6th semester student of the Informatics Engineering Study Program, Faculty of Engineering, Raja Ali Haji Maritime University (UMRAH). During college I started to get to know the world of IT which really attracted my attention to continue developing my innovation and creativity. I also have a focus in the IT field such as Web Development, UI/UX Design and Data Analysis. Through the projects I have worked on previously, my ability has increased in terms of solving complex problems and managing time effectively to ensure the success of a project.

EDUCATION

Raja Ali Haji Maritime University (UMRAH)

September 2021 - Present

Bachelor 1 Informatics Engineering GPA: 3.71/4.0

I studied at Raja Ali Haji Maritime University (UMRAH) Faculty of Engineering with the Study Program:

Informatics Engineering

Dian Nuswantoro University (UDINUS)

March - July 2024

I took part in the 4th batch of independent student exchange program organized by the Ministry of Education, Culture, Research and Technology at Dian Nuswantoro University for 1 semester and took courses with a track at the Faculty of Computer Science, Dian Nuswantoro University:

- Informatics Engineering
- Information Systems

Lingga 1 Public High School

September 2015-March 2018

· Mathematics and natural science

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Design of Information Systems and Management of New

September - December 2023

Students at SD Negeri 013 Tanjungpinang Barat_(Project)

Programmers and Developers (Team)

- Do research and see what conditions are needed at SDN 013 Tanjungpinang Barat.
- Providing innovation in the development of renewable technology.
- Implementation of new technology at SDN 013 Tanjungpinang Barat.

Raja Ali Haji Maritime University (UMRAH) Website Profile Design (Project)

September - December 2023

UI/UX Design and Website Programming (Individual)

- Designing the UI/UX design of the Raja Ali Haji Maritime University (UMRAH) Profile Website.
- Building a website profile for the Raja Ali Haji Maritime University (UMRAH).
- Implementation of an employee attendance system.

Building a Distributed Chat Based Website (Project)

September - December 2023

Programmers and Developers (Team)

- Website-based chat system distribution settings.
- Manage and orchestrate distributed chat system replication using VirtualBox.
- Back up chat data with a virtual machine to avoid data loss.

Building an Arduino Uno Based Attendance System (*Project*)

Arduino Device Assembler and Programmer (Team)

February - July 2023

- Building a digital attendance system based on Arduino Uno.
- Manage student attendance through a digital system and can be exported in Excel form to make it easier to record student attendance data.
- Implementation of IoT system developments.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

GEMASTIK XV National Student Performance in the Field of ICT (Certificate)

Programming Division (Team)

- October November 2022

 Become a participant in the representative programming division of the Raja Ali Haji Maritime University (UMRAH).
- Deepen programming skills and good team collaboration.

Appreciation of the Ambassador Event and National Planning Generation

December 2020

Creativity Jamboree (Certificate)

National Level GenRe Creativity Jamboree Participants (Team)

- Become a Representative for the Riau Archipelago Province in the National ADUJAK GenRe activities.
- · Contribute to youth creative activities.

Appreciation of GenRe Ambassador for Riau Islands Province (Certificate)

August 2020

- GenRe Kabputane Lingga Ambassador Representative (Individual) • Become a representative of Lingga Regency in the GenRe Ambassador event for Riau Islands Province.
- Contributing to the youth generation of the Riau Islands province and becoming an Ambassador for the Planning Generation of the Riau Islands Province.
- Get the title of best costume as the Riau Islands Province GenRe Ambassador award. Lingga Regency GenRe Ambassador (Information)

April 2020

Lingga Regency Elected GenRe Ambassador (Individual)

- Opportunity to become a driving force for the Planning Generation in Lingga Regency.
- Contributing as a Planning Generation Ambassador for Lingga Regency.
- Representing Lingga Regency in the selection of GenRe Ambassadors for Riau Islands Province.

Riau Islands Province Indonesian Language Debate Competition (Certificate) Third Debate Speaker in Indonesian (Team)

April 2019

- Become the third speaker in defending your argument.
- Playing the role of a debator in the Indonesian language debate competition at the high school level in the Riau Islands Province.
- Become a representative of the Indonesian Language Debate participants at SMA Negeri 1 Lingga.

Level IV Scout Competition for Riau Islands Province

August 2018

Lingga Regency Representative (Team)

- Experienced in the environment at Regency and Provincial levels.
- Received 3rd place in the LT IV Boy Scouts for Riau Islands Province.
- Become a representative of Lingga Regency as a participant in the LT IV Scout Campaign at the Provincial level.

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Volunteers for Basic Leadership Training (LDK) in Informatics Engineering Public Relations/PR Division (Team)

March - April 2023

Assist in organizing and implementing LDK activities.

• Fostering and guiding friends in the Informatics Engineering environment.

Chair of the Lingga Regency GenRe Forum

September 2019 - September 2020

Chairman (GenRe Forum)

- Managed the Lingga Regency GenRe Forum for 1 Period.
- Have experience as a leader in a forum at the district level.
- Speaking at the Lingga Regency GenRe Forum for 1 period.

Chairman of PIK-Teenager BERTUAH SMAN 1 Lingga Chairman of the organization)

August 2019 - September 2020

- Leading a positive and productive PIK-Teen BERTUAH Organization.
- Become a Counselor and Peer Educator for fellow students at SMA Negeri 1 Lingga.
- Become a Facilitator of PIK-Teenager activities at the School, District, Regency and Provincial levels.

SKILLS

Hard Skill

- Microsoft Office (Word, Power Point, Excel), Canva and Figma.
- Design UI/UX, HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, MySQL, Python, C and C++.

- Leadership, Teamwork, Problem Solving and Quick to Adapt.
- Indonesian (Active), Malaysian (Active) and English (Passive).

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Publication: Journal of Information Systems Design and Management of New Students at SD Negeri 013 Tanjungpinang Barat. (Journal)
- Achievement: Recipient of Student Creativity Program (PKM) funds from the Ministry of Education and Culture. (Capaian)